# ADAMU M. DANKORE

Charles City, Iowa 50616 || (319) 296-5799 adamu.dankore@gmail.com || https://www.dankore.com

#### SUMMARY

An experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Skilled in JavaScript, React, Ruby, MongoDB, Express, Node, marketing and launching startups. Strong engineering and design professional with over 12 million impressions of design work on Facebook.

# **TOOL STACKS / COMPETENCIES**

JavaScript • Node.js • React • Express • Ruby • MongoDB • Front-End Web Development • Back-End Web Development • Data Structures • Bootstrap • Tailwind CSS • HTML5 • CSS3 • NoSQL • Object Oriented Programming • GitHub • Gitlab • Marketing • Design • Social Media Marketing • Version Control • Problem Solving • Client/Server Side • Ajax • Management • MVC Architecture • Databases • Slack • Troubleshooting • JSON • REST API • Modern Web Security • GIT • SEO • Teamwork • SAP • JSX • SPA • SQL • Access • VBA

#### **EXPERIENCE**

HOME AWAY FROM HOME

# **Software Engineer and Head of Marketing**

Remote, Part-Time November 2018 - Present

- Lead a small marketing team which grew the startup to 4,000 unique visits and 400,000 SSL requests a month
- Wrote Hyperapp code running in a Docker Swam cluster
- Increased brand visibility through product design, targeted marketing, and content addition
- Designed and implemented views using Tailwind CSS

**CAMBREX** 

# Process Support Chemist and Full Stack Developer

Charles City, Iowa November 2017 – Present

- Our site saved the company more than Seven Million U.S. Dollars from 2017 to date
- Perform chemical testing on a variety of pharmaceutical-grade instruments such as HPLC, GC, NMR, and FTIR
- Developing productivity MS Access applications for use by laboratory personnel
- One of my technical suggestions is used by our lab manager to facilitate effective and money-saving communication

### **FREELANCE**

# Full Stack Web Developer and Designer

January 2018 - Present

- Designed and developed custom websites for clients based on specifications
- Gained over 12 million impressions and 230k shares of graphic design work on Facebook
- · Collaborated and worked iteratively with clients to determine the necessary project requirements

## **PROJECTS**

## GSS GWARINPA NETWORK | http://www.gssgwarinpa.com

- · Developed a social networking app for current and past students of my former secondary school
- Implemented modern web security features to protect users' personal data
- The site has been receiving positive feedback from students and alumni and continues to grow day-by-day

#### MS ACCESS DATABASE PROJECTS | Internal Company Applications

- Developing an app that would utilize the company's analytical tests database to send uniform end-of-shift email report
- Developing a user-driven project-based MS Access database that would allow chemists to sign up for volunteer projects
- Both projects are expected to boost productivity and communication amongst laboratory personnel

# **EDUCATION**

# **B.A in Chemistry & Minor in Leadership**

Wartburg College, Waverly, Iowa Honors: Dean's list

# CERTIFICATIONS / TECHNICAL EDUCATION

App Academy's Intro to Ruby • FreeCodeCamp's Responsive Web Design • SoloLearn's JavaScript Course • Adult First Aid/CPR/AED • MongoDB Essentials - Understand the Basics of MongoDB (Udemy) • VSchool's Learn React: A Comprehensive Introduction